Guide to the Daniel C. (Daniel Cowan) Jackling Papers, 1911-1956
Department of Special Collections
Daniel C. (Daniel Cowan) Jackling Papers,
1911-1956
Special Collections M0093
Jackling, Daniel C. (Daniel Cowan), 1869-1956.
47.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Partially restricted: for more more information contact the manuscripts librarian.
Restrictions protecting the privacy of living individuals control the use of this collection. Full details may be found in the "Petition for Instructions" presented by Musick, Peeler, and Garrett, attorneys-at-law, in the Superior Court of the State of California in and for the county of San Mateo (copy in D.C. Jackling file, Stanford University Libraries Department of Special Collections.
Provenance
Gift of Jackling Estate, 1964.
Scope and Content
This collection includes material organized in four series: Private Papers, Personal Papers, Photographs and Printed Matter, and Ledgers and Accounts.
There is little distinction between the private and personal papers except that this is the manner in which they were kept in Mr. Jackling's office and this is the arrangement which is preserved at Stanford. The Private Files are essentially corespondence with business acquaintances, especially Erle E. Daveler of the New York office of Kennecott. This file also contains letters on the subject of Kennecott Copper's reorganization in 1936 and the acquisition of Utah Copper by Kennecott Copper. Miscellaneous correspondence to friends and smaller numbers of business papers complete this series.
The Personal Files, with the exception of some weeding of printed matter, have been left as they were filed in Mr. Jackling's office. They cover a wide range of topics including art objects, Missouri School of Mines, Clubs and Societies, donations, investments, liquor inventories, property, relatives, taxes and publicity (under which are filed numerous periodical articles about Jackling and mining properties he was concerned with). The bulk of the correspondence in this section dates from 1917-1956.
The photographs and the printed matter deal with Jackling and properties he was associated with.
The ledgers and accounts are of the D. C. and Virginia Jackling Trusts, financial affairs and the Woodside, California farm.
Biographical Note
Daniel Cowan Jackling, born 4 August 1869 in Appleton, Missouri, was a mining engineer. He was instrumental in the establishment of several mining companies and the development of mining areas in the Western United States. He was associated with Kennecott Copper for many years. He died in 1956.
1869, August 4. Born in Appleton, Missouri.
1892 B.S. from Missouri School of Mines, Rolla, Missouri.
1892-3 Assistant Professor of Chemistry and Metallurgy, Missouri School of Mines.
1894-5 Employed at Cripple Creek, Colorado.
1896 Employed at Mercur, Utah.
1900 Met.E. from Missouri School of Mines
1900 Employed at Republic, Washington.
1903 Employed at Colorado City, Colorado.
1904 Instrumental in the establishment of Utah Copper Co. with mine at Bingham, Utah. In later years, successively Managing Director, Vice President and President of Utah Copper.
1905-7 Consulting Engineer in the development of Nevada Mines at Ely, Nevada. Successively Managing Director, Vice President and President of the Nevada Consolidated Copper Corporation.
1907-9 Developed mines at Ray, Arizona. Successively General Manager, Managing Director, Vice President and President of Ray Consolidated Copper Company.
1909 Similar development of Chino Copper Company.
1910-11 Participated in the organization, development and equipment of the Butte and Superior Mining Company properties at Butte, Montane. Later President of that Company.
1912 President of Utah Power and Light Company.
1912 Developed and equipped the properties of the Alaska Gold Mines at Juneau, Alaska.
1915 Developed low-grade magnetite iron ores of Mesabi range. President of the Mesabi Iron Company.
1917 Associated with Callup American Coal Company, Callup, New Mexico.
1918 Assistant to the U. S. Director of Purchases, Storage and Traffic, on the U.S. Army General Staff
1919 Married Virginia Jolliffe of San Francisco.
1926 Awarded the Cold Medal of the Mining and Metallurgical Society of America.
1930 Awarded William Lawrence Saunders Gold Medal of the American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers.
1933 Awarded the John Fritz Medal of the Engineering Societies of New York.
1933 D. Eng. from Missouri School of Mines, Honorary.
1940 Honorary LL.D. University of California. Honorary Dr. of Eng. University of Southern California.
1942 Honorary Sc.D. University of Utah. Retired from Kennecott Copper positions.
1954 Statue placed in rotunda of Utah Capitol Building.
1956 Died March 13.
Series Description
- Private Files. So marked by Mr. Jackling's office assistants, Additions to this series include materials unlabeled when received and placed here as a matter of convenience. (Box 1-18)
  filed alphabetically by subject.
- Personal Files. So marked by Mr. Jackling's office assistants and numbered by them. (Box 19-81)
  Files arranged by number which is roughly alphabetical and checked in a guide (see #99) made by Jackling's office staff.
- Photographs. (Box 82)
- Printed Matter. Reports, etc. concerning the various mines Jackling was associated with. (Box 83-90)
- Ledgers and accounts. (Box 91-107)
Container List
- PRIVATE FILES
  Daniel C. Jackling File - so named by Mr. Jackling's secretaries. In some cases the Private files and Personal files (see below) are similar, in which case cross references are given to the Personal file. A limited amount of transferring from the Private to the Personal files was also made.
  - Chase National Bank, 1933-1937.D. C. Jackling was on the board and indirectly involved in a suit brought against the bank. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - French and Company and Meredith Galleries 1918-1949.Regarding tapestries. See also Containers 27-28. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Financial statements, 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Genealogy. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Health and retirement and other personal subjects, 1930-1954. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personal Taxes, 1932.See Containers 70-76. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Railroad pass matter, 1933. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yacht Cyprus, 1934.See also ledgers. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yacht Cyprus, 1929-1943(See Container 91 for plans of the yacht). (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alexander, H. F., 1927-1937(See also Container 44). (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Bell, H. G. (trustee), 1937-1956. (Box 2, Folder 3-7)
  - Bennett, W. E., 1932. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Boyd, W. S., 1928-1940. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Brewster, Burt B., 1942-1955.(Deceased-see obit in folder 3) (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
  - Buchman, Louis, 1945-1947(See also Container 45). (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carrier, Dr. F. N., 1937-1938. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cates, L. S., 1928-1948(See also Container 46. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cowan, W. B., 1911-1914. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Daveler, Erle, E., 1932-1941. (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Daveler, Erle E., 1942-1944. (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
  - Daveler, Erle E., 1944-1946. (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
  - Daveler, Erle E., 1946-1949. (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
  - Daveler, Erle E., 1950-1956. (Box 8, Folder 13-16)
  - Fleishhacker, Herbert (Admiral Oriental Line), 1933,also H. F. Alexander. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hayden, Charles - General, 1927-1932. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hayden, Charles - Securities, 1928-1936.(See also Container 47). (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hickey, G. L., 1934-1940. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Jenkins, C. V., 1926-1931. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Jolliffe, Miss Harriet H., 1935-1940. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Kinnear, J. C., 1928-1942(See also Container 48). (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - McLean, A. J., 1927-1947(See also Container 49). (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
  - MacGowan, John K., 1929-1932. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - MacWhinney, E. S., 1939-1942(See also Container 49) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Moffitt, Dr. and Mrs. H. C., 1928(See also Container 69). (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Moffat, D. D., 1931-1942(See also Container 48). (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Nowland, R. C., 1934-1942re: estate of Charles Hayden. (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
  - Parsons, C. C., 1943-1944(See also Container 49) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Penrose, Mrs. Spencer, 1941. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Ronaghan, A. J., 1928-1933. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Sapello (Percy Wilson), 1929-1931(See also Container 39). (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Stone, Robert O., 1937-1946(See also Container 11 and 50). (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Tooker, H. B., 1934-1942(See also Container 51). (Tooker deceased; see A. J. [unk] correspondence in Box 9 folders 8-10) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Utah Security purchases, 1930. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Stone, Robert O., 1946-1956(See also Container 10 & 50). (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
  - Negotiations for new contract with Asarco and option on half interest in Garfield Smelter, 1939-1940(See also Container 90). (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Alaska Mining & Power Company, 1934-1935. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Braden Copper Company, 1940. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Kennecott reorganization. 1938. (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
  - Relative share value of Kennecott and Nevada, 1929-1933. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Kennecott reorganization, 1938. (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Acquisition of Nevada by Kennecott, 1932-1933. (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Calumet and Hecla Copper Company, 1925-1926. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Copper exporters, 1930-1937. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Copper industry investigation, 1938-1939. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Gallup American Coal Company, 1942. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - International Exploration Corporation, 1937. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - International Exploration Corporation Minutes, 1929-1937.(See also Container 77). (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Steamship-Admiral Oriental Line, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Santa Barbara Oil Syndicate, 1929-1932. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Consolidation, Ray, Chino, Nevada, Inspiration, 1923.(See also Container 18). (Box 15, Folder 9-11)
  - Consolidation, Ray, Chino, Nevade, Inspiration, 1924.(See also Container 18). (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Ray Hercules Mining Company, 1926. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Ray-Chino Smelting Contract-Old Papers, 1926. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Ray-Chino Smelting Contract-Secondary papers, 1926-1927. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Production and Costs-Utah and Nevada (Working papers- June 10, 1931). (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Utah Copper Company - Ten year program, 1936-1940. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Utah Copper Company, 1936details on expansion program. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Acquisition of Utah by Kennecott, 1936-1937. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - List of Jackling-Gemmell files in SLC. (Old Files in Room 411). (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Index to Files in box in closet in Mr. Jackling's office. (Files which are not included in this collection). (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous papers not integrated into Miles by Jackling office staff.
    - Consolidation, Ray-Inspiration, 1924.(See also Container 15 and 16). (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Chino, Ray, Nevada evaluation sheets and merger conference, 1923. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Private value of properties, Nevada and Chino 1928-1930. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Certificates of Organization, Nevada, Chino and Ray. 1923. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Ore sections (Map) Chino, 1923. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Summary of evaluations, Kennecott and Utah, 1927. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Memorandum relative to service of D.C. Jackling to the Braden Copper Company of Chile. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Kennecott papers, 1951 and 1954 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Garfield Smelter purchase option, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Mesabi Iron Ore Company figures. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Kansas City Structural Steel, 1943-1954. (Box 18, Folder 11)
- PERSONAL FILES
  The remaining files were marked Mr. Jackling's Personal rather Private papers. They are generally numbered and have been left in numerical order as received from the Estate. The number assigned by Mr. Jackling's office staff appears in parentheses at the end of each folders listing.
  - Accounts and Finance. Present worth calculations. 1915-1923., (0-116). (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Insurance, group and retirement. 1940-1954., (0-395 part 3). (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Publicity matters, History of Utah Copper Company. 1919-1930., (1-622). (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Relations with other companies, Alaska Mining and Power Company-miscellaneous, 1933-1941., (0-667-2). (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Relations with other companies, Alaska Gold Mines Company-reorganization, 1931-1937, (0-667). (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Relations with other companies, Alaska Mining & Power Company-Alaska Juneau Mining Company, 1915-1935, (0-667-4). (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous A letters, 1946-1955, 1000-A pt. 2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous B letters, 1948-1955, 1000-B (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous C letters, 1952-1955, 1000-C (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous C letters, 1946-1952, (1000-C pt.). (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous D letters, 1945-1953, (1000-D pt.2). (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous E letters, 1946-1956, (1000-E pt.2). (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous F letters, 1946-1956, (1000-F pt.3). (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous G letters, 1946-1956, (1000-G pt.3). (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous H letters, 1953-1956, (1000-H pt.2). (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous H letters, 1947-1953, (1000-H pt. 5). (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous J letters, 1947-1956, (1000-J pt.2). (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous K letters, 1947-1955, (1000-K pt.2). (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous L letters, 1948-1956, (1000-L pt.3). (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous L letters, (Austin Larick) 1953-1956, (1000-L pt.4). (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous M letters, 1947-1956, (1000-M pt.4). (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Mc letters, 1947-1956, (1000-Mc). (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous N letters, 1947-1956, (1000-N). (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous O letters, 1947-1955, (1000-0). (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous P letters, 1948-1954, (1000-P pt.3). (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous P letters, 1955-1956, (1000-P pt.4). (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Q letters, 1927-1941, (1000-Q). (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous R letters, 1947-1956, (1000-R pt.2). (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous S letters, 1947-1955, (1000-S). (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous T letters, 1947-1956, (1000-7 pt. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous U letters, 1947-1956, (1000-U). (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous V letters, 1947-1951, (1000-V). (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous W letters, 1948-1955, (1000-W). (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous X-Y-Z letters, 1948-1955, (1000-X-Y-Z). (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Association Missouri School of Mines, 1931-1933, (1085 pt.1). (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Association Missouri School of Mines, 1933-1941, (1085 pt.2). (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Association Missouri School of Mines, 1942-1955, (1085 pt.3). (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Missouri School of Mines, 1922-1936, (1085-1 pt.1) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Missouri School of Mines, 1936-1944, (1085-1 pt.2) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Missouri School of Mines, 1944-1946, (1085-1 pt.3) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Missouri School of Mines, 1946-1950, (1085-1 pt.4) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Missouri School of Mines, Conferring of honorary degree upon Mr. Jackling, 1933., (1085-3). (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Missouri School of Mines, Jackling Loan Fund, 1909-1955. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Political 1942-1956[contributions and some expressions of political beliefs by DCJ]., (1115). (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Art objects, general. 1919-1955, (2000). (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Art objects, George Ainslee, 1916-1937, (2003). (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Art objects, coins. 1915-1952, (2022). (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Art objects, fure and skins, C.W. DuBois, 1916-1923, (2026). (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Art objects - J. E. French and Company, 1927-1935, (2037 pt.1). (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Art objects. French and Company and Brudley Dolehanty. 1935-1950, (2037 pt.2). (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Art objects, S. & G. Gump. 1914-1953, (2046). (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Art objects, A. L. Groll. 1917, (2048). (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Art objects, J. E. Henson. 1912-1923, (2061). (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Art objects, George M. Knosdler. 1916-1937, (2070). (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Art objects, John S. Keshishyan. 1921-1936, (2071). (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Art objects, Kent-Costikyan (Marx & Jones), 1914-1950, (2072). (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
  - Art objects, Jonas Lie. 1917-1940, (2085). (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Art objects, Arthur Upham Pope. 1918-1924, (2115). (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Art objects, Private library. 1920-1948, (2086). (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Banking, Anglo & London Paris National Bank. 1917-1937, (3005). (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Banking, Bingham State Bank. 1922-1929, (3016). (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Banking, Crocker First National Bank. 1917-1956, (3026). (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Banking, First National Bank-Redwood City. 1940-1951, (3038). (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Banking, First National Bank of Salt Lake City. 1947-1948, (3039). (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Employees, Twenty year gold service medal (Utah Copper). 1939-1954, (1-3010). (Box 29, Folder 7)
- CLUBS AND SOCIETIES
  - General, 1951-1954, (4000) (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Alta Club. 1919-1956, (4003). (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Army Ordnance Association. 1923-1953, (4007). (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers, San Francisco Section. 1952-1954, (4008). (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - A.I.M. & M.E. Award of Saunders Medal to Mr. Jackling. 1930-1931, (4008-1). (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - A.I.M. & M.E. Saunders Gold Medal Committee. 1934-1942, (4008-2). (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - A.I.M. & M.E. 1948-1950, (4008-3 pt.10). (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - A.I.M. & M.E. 1952-1955, (4008-3 pt. 11). (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - A.I.M. & M.E. 1953-1956, (4008-3 pt.12). (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Various donations to A. I. M. & M. E. and Women's Auxiliary. 1938-1952, (4008-4). (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Honorary membership in A. I. M. & M. E. 1941, (4008-5). (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - El Paso Club, Colorado Springs, Colorado. 1915-1944, (4054). (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - The Engineer's Club of San Francisco. 1939- 1956, (4057). (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - The American Society of Mechanical Engineers. 1941-1952, (4058). (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Mining and Metallurgical Society of America. 1944-1956, (4097). (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Mining and Metallurgical Society of America. 1925-1927.Awarding gold medal to Mr. Jackling., (4097-1). (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Mercur (Utah) Pioneer Society. 1931-1946, (4099). (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Pacific Railway Club. 1920-1956, (4131). (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Phelps County (Mo.) Historical Society. 1942-1945, (4134). (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - The Great American Prospectors Association. 1935-1953, (4168). (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Western Society of Engineers, Washington Award 1940-1956, (4184). (Box 31, Folder 5)
    ( END OF CLUBS AND SOCIETIES)
  - Donations, miscellaneous requests, (5000 pt. 2-6). (Box 31, Folder 6-10)
  - Donations, Boys Club of San Francisco, (5015). (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Donations, Boy Scouts of America, (5018). (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Donations, Community Chest, (5020). (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Donations, Committee for Constitutional Government, (5031). (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Donations, Central Missouri State College (Memorial Chapel Fund) 1953-1956, (5032). (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Donations, Employees, St. Francis & Mark Hopkins Hotels, 1917-1933, (5037). (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Donations, Red Cross, 1942-1955, (5109). (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Donations, Salvation Army, 1919-1955, (5129). (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Donations, Western Tax Council, Inc., (5150). (Box 32, Folder 5)
- INVESTMENTS
  - Hayden, Stone and Company, 1923-1955, (6000). (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Hayden, Stone and Company, consolidation of accounts 1935-1943, (6000-1). (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1935-1955, (6002). (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Buck Creek Oil Venture (Spring Creek Venture, Utah) 1938-1953, (6024). (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Calmaxico Petroleum Corp., 1928-1930, (6027 pt. 1). (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Calmexico Petroleum Corp., 1930-1948, (6027 ptc. 2-5). (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - Copper Canyon Mining Company, Nevada, 1937-1938, (6029). (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Colorado Midland Railway, 1917-1921, (6036). (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Busk Ivanhoe Company, Colorade, 1922-1950, (6036). (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - California Tennis Club, 1925-1948, (6040). (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Dean Witter & Company, General, 1943-1948, (6041-2). (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Dollar Steamship Line, 1924-1939, (6042). (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Eggers' Tungsten property, (6043). (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Davis Steel Process Corporation, 1927-1931, (6044 pt.1). (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Davis Steel Process Corporation, 1931-1949, (6044 pt. 2). (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - El Paso Natural Gas Company, 1937-1955, (6046). (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - First Security Corporation of Utah, 1929-1947, (6048). (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Garden City Sugar and Land Company of Colorado and Kansas, 1911-1956, (6053). (Box 35, Folder 4-6)
  - Empyre Fire Extinguisher Corp., 1942-1946, (6065). (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Jackling trust account, 1917-1928See also Container 59 and ledgers at end of cartons., (6076). (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - D. C. Jackling trust, 1926-1948See also Container 58 and ledgers at end of cartons., (6077 pt. 1-2). (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
  - Jolliffe trust, Mrs. Gertrude Aller, trustee, 1924-1950, (6079). (Box 36, Folder 5-6)
  - Kansas City (No.) Structural Steel Company, 1915-1951, (6083). (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
  - Kennecott Copper Corporation, 1915-1950, (6085). (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Lovell (Wyoming) Refinery, 1919-1922, (6091). (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
  - Lovell (Wyoming) Refinery, 1923-1948, (6091). (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
  - Mesabi Iron Company, 1915-1957, (6105). (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Oravada Venture, 1940, (6118). (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Pioche Metals Mining Company, 1908-1958, (6129). (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Pond Creek Pocahontas Company (Coal), 1933-1958, (6130). (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Rip Van Winkle Mining Company (Utah), 1938-1953, (6134). (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Ritter-Chapin Oil Enterprise in Montana (1944), (6135). (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Sapello Company, New Mexico (G. O. S. Cattle Co.) 1923-1926, 1931-1934See also P. W. Sapello, Container 10., (6139 pt. 1 & 5). (Box 39, Folder 6-8)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission. 1934-1943, (6141). (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Silver Burro Exploration Company (Ray Brooks), 1938-1945, (6142). (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Texas Gulf Sulphur, 1915-1925, (6146). (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
  - Texas Gulf Sulphur, 1925-1955, (6146). (Box 41, Folder 1-3)
  - Tri-State Oil and Refining Company (Western Oil Fields, Inc., Denver, Colorade), (1938-1961), (6149). (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Utah Southern Oil Company, 1923-1940, (6156). (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
  - Wyoming Eastern (Allen) Oil Company, 1916-1936, (6168). (Box 42, Folder 4-6)
    (END OF INVESTMENTS)
  - Report on test run on the Magna and Arthur Plants of the Utah Copper Company, 1910. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Reports and Statistics, Special geological reports on Utah Copper, H. U. Winchell and R. N. Hunt, 1921, (6822). (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Reports and Statistics, Special geological reports on Utah Copper. Statement by James F. Kemp, 1905, (6823). (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Reports and Statistics, Special geological reports. Old reports by Clement and Spillsbury, 1904, (6826). (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Insurance, Jewelry and Personal effects, (7013). (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Insurance, life, (7017). (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Itineraries, European trip, 1928-1929, (8009). (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Itineraries, trip to England, 1937, (8011). (Box 43, Folder 8)